

# **Craig Carter**

Phone: (562) 547-7845

Email: <a href="mailto:craigcarter42@gmail.com">craig\_carter@apple.com</a>

linkedin.com/in/craig-carter42 github.com/craigcarter42

## **Profile**

With over six years of experience as a technician, I am a confident self-starter who works well independently and can thrive working in teams while delivering quality products and services. I am driven by my passion for technology and problem-solving in fast-paced work environments.

# Work Experience

### Genius, Apple | San Francisco, CA - March 2017-Present

- Drives results at Genius Bar by multitasking with 2-3 customers reducing their wait time and proving solutions.
- Uses acquired knowledge and problem solving skills when triaging issues with customer systems.
- Works with customers to carefully document concerns while offering solutions and next steps.
- Meticulously completes hardware repairs following company standards to assure longevity of repaired product.
- · Partners with management to innovate around repair strategies and reduce turnaround time by 2 days.

## CE with Platform Restore QA, Apple | Cupertino, CA - January 2019-July 2019

- Screened 500+ results daily from automation testing for regressions in current software build.
- Triaged daily automation failures to find root cause and escalated bug reports to responsible teams.
- · Organized and maintained lab equipment to improve team efficiency by providing needed resources quickly.
- Performed manually testing of new software builds to check for graphical anomalies during the update process.
- · Completed weekly preflight tests for engineering to validate code changes before being merged to mainline.
- Procured and setup wireless isolation chambers for Apple Watch testing which increased testing success by 50%.
- Created Python tool to find update assets during manual testing which prevented human error and saved time.

# Technical Specialist, Apple | San Francisco, CA — April 2014-March 2017

- Achieved session productivity to positively impact customer wait time and repair turnaround time.
- Supported on average 30 customers a day with technical needs at the Genius Bar.
- Utilized diagnostic tools and triaging skills to provide accurate diagnoses of customer reported issues.
- Educated customers how to maximize their technology to reduce their dependance on Genius Bar support.
- Provided careful documentation of device issues to assist with device repair or bug escalation.

#### Tier II Technical Support Engineer, Leap Motion | San Francisco, CA - Jan 2013-Sep 2013

- Provided phone and email support to customers experiencing issues with newly released product.
- Worked with a team to troubleshoot trending technical issues and escalated bugs for further review.
- Documented and managed customer interactions using tickets in the internal CRM system.
- Assisted with identifying trends with customer questions and concerns by sharing feedback with team.

#### Software and Hardware Skills

Python, Bash, Shell Scripting, Command Line, Git, Ansible, Docker, Nginx, Linux, Unix, Radar, Apple (all platforms), Raspberry Pi, Arduino, Teensy Board

# **Technical Skills**

Problem Solving, Grey & Black Box Testing, Automation Triage, Collecting and Analyzing Crash Logs

#### Education

UC Berkeley Extension | Certificate Program in Software Development and Programming (Expected completion June 2022)

## Certifications

(ACMT) Apple Certified Mac Technician (ACIT) Apple Certified iOS Technician